The Lives Of The Prophets Part 1,
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ
Abrahim عليه السّلام came to Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل)
by the way, Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) made many visits to Makkah.
One of these visits in a Hadith(حديث) narrated by Bukhari(بخاريْ);
Ibrahim عليه السّلام comes to Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) and tell him, we have been commanded to build the house of Allah.
So Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) started building the house of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
The spot of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه), the spot itself is sacred and holy since the earth was created.
It's a sacred land since the time of Adam(آدَم).
And that spot was known and Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) used to make Hajj(حَجْ) to that area, the spot itself.
But there is a dispute and difference among the Ulama(علماء) whether Adam(آدَم) has built anything over there or not.
Most likely, the first one who established the house is Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم).
But the spot itself was holy from before.
It didn't become holy, the moment in which Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)  was built on it.
No! That spot itself is, is holy and sacred, just like Al-Masjid Al-Aqsa(ألمسجد ألأقصي),
when Rasool Allah ﷺ visited the Al-Masjid Al-Aqsa(ألمسجد ألأقصي) in the trip of Al-Isra(ألأسراء), there wasn't anything built there.
In fact, when Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) opened Jerusalem it was used as a dumpster there was garbage in that spot.
But still that was Al-Masjid Al-Aqsa(ألمسجد ألأقصي)  that was the holy sacred mosque.
And then the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم and in the time of Abdul Malik Bin Marwan(عبدالملك بن مروان) they built the two mosques that are enclosed in that Haram(حرم),
but before it was a piece of land.
What makes it special, it's a piece of land.?
What makes Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) the land under it special, when it's a desert and nothing grows there.
It's desert what makes it special?
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
يَخْلُقُ مَا يَشَآءُ وَيَخْتَارُ ۗ
Allah  creates everything He wants, and He chooses out of them.
Allah chooses the best, Allah chooses the worst, Allah chooses what is in between, it's up to Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Allah is the One, Who created the days and Allah is the One, Who chose the best of them to be Friday.
Allah is the One, Who created the days of the year and chose Eid- Al-Ad'haa(عيدالأضحى) and Eid-Ul-Fitr(عيدالفطر) to be the best.
Allah created the month and chose Ramadan(رمضان) to be the holy month of fasting.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is the One, Who created the days and gave the most reward for the 10 days of Dhul-Hijjah(ذوالحجة).
Allah is the One, Who created the nights and Allah has given the special rewards and the nights of Ramadan(رمضان).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى also created the nights and He has made the special night Lailat-Ul-Qadr(ليلة القدر).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى created the earth and He chose Makkah and Madina and Bat-Ul-Maqsad(بيت المقدس) to be special.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is the One, Who created human beings and they chose Muhammadﷺ to be the best among them.
يَخْلُقُ مَا يَشَآءُ وَيَخْتَارُ ۗ
Allah creates whatever He wants and then He chooses of them.
So that area, it doesn't have to be a certain dimension and certain physical characteristics and certain shape and certain plants for it, to be special.
These are not the conditions and requirements that apply to Allahسُبحانه وتعالى
because Allah is free of all of these rules and regulations, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is the creator.
So that spot was holy sacred from the beginning of the creation of the earth.
Ibrahim عليه السّلام and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) started building the house, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَإِذ يَرفَعُ إِبراهيمُ القَواعِدَ مِنَ البَيتِ وَإِسماعيلُ رَبَّنا تَقَبَّل مِنّا ۖ إِنَّكَ أَنتَ السَّميعُ العَليمُ۝
And remember when Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and his son Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) were raising the foundations of the house.
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and Ismail عليه السّلام, when they were building the house of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى they had Dua(دُعَا).
رَبَّنا وَاجعَلنا مُسلِمَينِ لَكَ وَمِن ذُرِّيَّتِنا أُمَّةً مُسلِمَةً لَكَ وَأَرِنا مَناسِكَنا وَتُب عَلَينا ۖ
وَتُب عَلَينا ۖ إِنَّكَ أَنتَ التَّوّابُ الرَّحيمُ۝
رَبَّنا وَابعَث فيهِم رَسولًا مِنهُم يَتلو عَلَيهِم آياتِكَ وَيُعَلِّمُهُمُ الكِتابَ وَالحِكمَةَ وَيُزَكّيهِم ۚ
وَيُعَلِّمُهُمُ الكِتابَ وَالحِكمَةَ وَيُزَكّيهِم ۚ إِنَّكَ أَنتَ العَزيزُ الحَكيمُ۝
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says and remember when Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and his son Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل), were raising the foundations of the house saying;
Our Lord accept the service from us verily You are the All Hearer, the All Knower, O Allah accept this from us.
Our Lord, and make us submissive unto You,
and of our offspring and nation submissive unto You,
and show us our Manasic(مناسك), the Hajj(حَجْ), how to do Hajj(حَجْ)?
Our Lord, send amongst them a messenger of their own,
who shall recite unto them Your verses and instruct them in the book and Sanctify them, verily you are Almighty and All Wise.
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل), they asked Allah to accept it from them.
And they asked Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to make them submissive to Allah; Muslimeen(مسلمين)
and they asked Allahسُبحانه وتعالى, to make their descendants submissive to Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And then they asked Allah to send among these people a Nabi(نَبِي).
Who's that Nabi(نَبِي) ?
Muhammadﷺ
Allah accepted the Dua(دُعَا).
They asked Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to give this Nabi(نَبِي) three things.
يَتْلُو عَلَيْهِمْ آيَاتِهِ
He recites unto them Your verses,
وَيُعَلِّمُهُمُ الكِتابَ وَالحِكمَةَ
He teaches them, the book and wisdom, what is wisdom?
Sunnah(سنة) of Rasool Allah ﷺ,
وَيُزَكّيهِم
Sanctify them and purify them.
So Muhammadﷺ  purifies us.
Tazkia(تزكية) purifies us.
Following the way of Muhammadﷺ is the purification for us.
Because if you look at the Da'wah(دعوة) of Muhammadﷺ, you see that he has started out with men that had hearts like rock.
And then look at how Rasool Allah ﷺ carried them from this state
and He elevated them to Make them the best generation that lived on the face of the earth.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى accepted the Dua(دُعَا) of Ibrahim عليه السّلام and sent to this Ummah(امة) Muhammadﷺ.
We'll finish up with the story of Ibrahim عليه السّلام by mentioning some of his qualities.
Ibrahim عليه السّلام is from Ulul Azm-e-Min-Ar-Rusul(اولي العزم من الرسل).
Ulul Azm-e-Min-Ar-Rusul(اولي العزم من الرسل) I can't find an exact translation of it.
But they are five Ulul Azm(اولي العزم) and these are the greatest of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah.
They are five; Muhammadﷺ, Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم), Musa(موسى), Eesa(عيسى) and Nuh(نوح).
And Ibn Kathir(اِبْنِ كَثِيْر) says that the second greatest among them after Muhammadﷺ is Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم).
Ibrahim عليه السّلام was mentioned the Qur'an about 73 times in 25 places.
Ibrahim عليه السّلام is the one, whom Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has called in Qur'an, Khalil-Ullah(خليل الله).
The friend of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Allah has chose Ibrahim عليه السّلام to be His friend.
Ibrahim عليه السّلام lived a lonely life.
He would travel from one place to another around the world making Hijrah(هجرة),
he lived in Iraq for a while in Harran(حرَّان), in Bait-Ul-Maqdis(بيت المقدس) in Egypt.
He visited Makkah few times.
All of this is traveling in difficult conditions.
And Ibrahim عليه السّلام was driven out of his homeland, no believers with him except his nephew, Lut(لوط)
and then he went all over these other countries and he didn't have many followers with him.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى told Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) that I am your friend.
You don't need any friends in this world; I'm your friend.
Also, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has given Ibrahim عليه السّلام a name that wasn't given to anybody else in Qur'an.
You know, when we're talking about Muhammadﷺ;
O Muhammadﷺ have patience and stay with the ones, who remember Allah in night and day.
Allah is commanding Muhammadﷺ to stay with the believers.
Nuh(نوح) when his people came and told them leave these weak people alone,
he said: No! These are the believers with me.
I will be with them; I will remain with them.
These Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) they had believers around them; Allahسُبحانه وتعالى told them to remain with these believers.
Why?
Because we need to have an environment of Eeman(ايمان).
We need to live in an environment of Eeman(ايمان), we need to have the support around us.
It's difficult for human being to live alone.
We need to have the support and Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is commanding Muhammadﷺ to stay with the believers.
Allah commanding Nuh(نوح) to stay with the believers.
We know that Hud(هود) was with the believer; Saleh(صالح) stayed with the believers;
Musa(موسى) stayed with the believers and so on and so forth.
Ibrahim عليه السّلام is different.
First of all, Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) was making Hijrah(هجرة) for his life.
And then in many places he would go; he would be the only believer.
He went to Egypt, he told his wife: Me and you are the only believers here.
When he was making  Da'wah(دعوة) to his people in Iraq, only him and Lut(لوط) were the believers.
So Allahسُبحانه وتعالى gave Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) a name that wasn't given to anybody else and that is;
كان أمة
he was nation by himself.
Ibrahim عليه السّلام was a nation, he was an Ummah(امة).
He didn't have anybody with him, he was alone; But Ibrahim عليه السّلام counts as a nation; as a whole Ummah(امة)
كان أمة
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said: Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) was an Ummah(امة)
and then Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said;
Kanitan(كانتًا)
He had a lot of Khushoo(خشوع); he had Khushoo(خشوع) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى in the night and day, 24 hours he was in the state of Khushoo(خشوع).
Kanatan Lillah(كانتًا لله)
and also Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
حَنِيفًا مُسْلِمًا وَمَا كَانَ مِنَ الْمُشْرِكِينَ۝
Hanif(حنيف), he stayed away from all Shirk(شرك).
Everyone was trying to pull him to Shirk(شرك); he stayed away from it and that is Hanif(حنيف).
It is Ikhlass Ala Basirah(إخلاص على بصيرة).
He has sincerity and understanding.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَإِذِ ابتَلىٰ إِبراهيمَ رَبُّهُ بِكَلِماتٍ فَأَتَمَّهُنَّ ۖ
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has tested Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) with some commands.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
فَأَتَمَّهُنَّ ۖ
He completed them all; He completed them all.
And that's why Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says about about Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم),
وَإِبْرَٰهِيمَ ٱلَّذِى وَفَّىٰٓ
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) has fulfilled; he fulfilled; he fulfilled what Allahسُبحانه وتعالى wanted from him; he fulfilled it all.
And Allah سبحانه وتعالى says about Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم),
قالَ إِنّي جاعِلُكَ لِلنّاسِ إِمامًا ۖ
I will make you an Imam(اِمَام), a leader for mankind,
someone who will be a role model for everyone to follow.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says about him;
وَجَعَلْنَا فِي ذُرِّيَّتِهِ النُّبُوَّةَ
We made all of the prophets after him, from his descendants.
All of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى and the Rusul(رسل) that came after Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم),
were from the descendants of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم).
This is the story of Sayidina  Ibrahim عليه السّلام.
We'll start with the story of Sayidina Lut(سيدنالوط).
Sayidina Lut عليه السّلام was sent to the people of Sadoom(سدوم), or Sodom in English.
He didn't belong to those people.
He was the nephew of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم), but he was sent on a mission to make Da'wah(دعوة) to those people.
And he made Da'wah(دعوة) to them
obviously always we find that the first thing the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) call to is;
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; Touheed(توحيد);
لا إله إلَّا الله
There is no God but Allah.
But we need to realize that
لا إله إلَّا الله
is not a word that is spoken only.
It is a way of life
and when we say,
لا إله إلَّا الله
We are saying that there is no god that should be worshipped except Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And no God should be followed except Allahسُبحانه وتعالى because there is no other God than Allah.
That would mean that the commandments and the orders and instructions should be taken from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
We notice that the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah, when they are dealing with their people;
they confront the problems of the society.
And they do not confront hypothetical situations, problems that are irrelevant or problems of the past;
they confront the diseases of the society,
they put their hand on the disease and they understand the symptoms of it and then they attack it
and that is very difficult thing to do.
It is very easy to make Da'wah(دعوة) to people; By giving them the things they want to hear,
and neglecting the things they don't want to hear.
For example, the people are suffering from a certain problem,
for example, we're dealing with a government that is ruling with the dictatorship.
We're not going to speak about the government leave that alone.
The people in front of me are smoking.
I'm not going to talk about smoking, I'm going to talk about something else.
The people that I'm dealing with are suffering from a problem of hijab(حجاب), the woman are not wearing hijab(حجاب).
Now, I'm gonna talk about the attack about Salah(صلاة); I'm not gonna talk about Hijab(حجاب);
That is controversial; eave it alone.
The people would love you as a Daiyah(داعية) they would love you
because you're letting them hear the things, they want to hear.
But that's not the way of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah;
the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah would attack the particular problem the society is suffering from
and that is what put the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah in trouble.
That is why all of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى suffered from the oppression of their people;
because the people don't want to hear about their mistakes,
people do not want you to tell them about their problems.
They don't want you to tell them that they're wrong.
People want you to make them feel that they're comfortable.
And they attack and they pinpoint the particular problem and they attack it;
All of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah, this is their way.
But in the Da'wah(دعوة) that we give today, very rarely do we follow this method, because we are weak.
But we need to follow the way of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى in their Da'wah(دعوة), it is very important;
because the religion of Allah comes to confront the particular problems that the people are facing with;
it did not come to deal with hypothetical problems and hypothetical issues and issues of the past.
The Ummah(امة) is suffering from problems today we need to face those problems
and not talk about things that are already dead or gone or things that didn't happen.
And that is why Lut عليه السّلام attacked the people and told them about the thing they don't want to hear about.
The people of Lut(لوط) were suffering from the disease of homosexuality.
That was a major disease that the society was suffering from.
That wasn't the only problem; They also had other problems related to that,
and that is that they were they were criminals.
They would rob the travelers, they would cause corruption in the land, they had very perverted hearts.
So Lut(لوط) told the people.
أَتَأتونَ الذُّكرانَ مِنَ العالَمينَ۝
وَتَذَرونَ ما خَلَقَ لَكُم رَبُّكُم مِن أَزواجِكُم ۚ بَل أَنتُم قَومٌ عادونَ۝
Go you in unto the males of the mankind and leave those, whom Allah has created for you to be your wives.
Nay you are trespassing people.
He told them this is that this thing you're doing is wrong.
The people of Lut(لوط) were very, very corrupt.
We read in these Ayaat(آيات), Lut(لوط) is telling his people.
وَلوطًا إِذ قالَ لِقَومِهِ أَتَأتونَ الفاحِشَةَ وَأَنتُم تُبصِرونَ۝
Lut(لوط) told his people do you commit this great sin; while you see one another.
The people of Lut(لوط) used to do this in public; in their clubs.
They wouldn't do it in secret and private; they would do it in public.
And they are the ones, who invented this sin.
Therefore, if anybody tells you that this is in the Jenes, that's not true,
because the people of Lut(لوط) are the ones, who invented it.
Now we find in America, they're trying to justify this action by saying that this is something by logical  in your in your jeans.
That's not the case because Lut عليه السّلام says;
وَلوطًا إِذ قالَ لِقَومِهِ إِنَّكُم لَتَأتونَ الفاحِشَةَ ما سَبَقَكُم بِها مِن أَحَدٍ مِنَ العالَمينَ۝
أَئِنَّكُم لَتَأتونَ الرِّجالَ وَتَقطَعونَ السَّبيلَ وَتَأتونَ في ناديكُمُ المُنكَرَ ۖ
And remember Lut(لوط) when he said to his people who commit sodomy, which none has preceded you and committing in the world.
Nobody did this before you are the ones, who invented this sin.
وَتَقطَعونَ السَّبيلَ
And you would rob the traveler,
وَتَأتونَ في ناديكُمُ المُنكَرَ ۖ
And you would commit sins in your clubs.
They have these clubs in which they would drink and they would commit these sins, in their clubs, in public.
Very evil.
And the people of Lut(لوط), they completely lost a concept of shame, they had no shame, no haya(حيا).
Because when you reached to the level where you would commit such a thing in public,
that tells you that these people had no haya(حيا), no shame, whatsoever.
And this is something that we find in the West today.
Among men and among women, there is no shyness,
being shy, is a negative characteristic.
You're supposed to be assertive and aggressive and outgoing and loud and noisy.
And I've seen from some of the sisters, for example,
that the Hijab(حجاب) is only a show from the outside,
but from the inside, it's homegrown in America,
and I've seen it, for example, in conventions,
you find that young Muslim sisters are bumping into the brothers and pushing them around and screaming in the elevators and laughing loudly.
This is something that you cannot see in Muslim countries when you go to the rural areas,
there is shyness,
this Haya(حيا) is lost, this Haya(حيا) is lost, even from the Muslims who are living in the West.
And these are very important qualities because Haya(حيا) is a branch of Eeman(ايمان)
and Haya(حيا) is not only for the woman, it's also for the men.
Haya(حيا) is for the men and women.
The people have Lut(لوط) when they heard this message that Lut(لوط) is telling them that what you're doing is wrong.
وَما كانَ جَوابَ قَومِهِ إِلّا أَن قالوا أَخرِجوهُم مِن قَريَتِكُم ۖ إِنَّهُم أُناسٌ يَتَطَهَّرونَ۝
And the answer of his people was only that they said; Drive them out of your town.
Why?
What was the justification given by the people of Lut(لوط),
إِنَّهُم أُناسٌ يَتَطَهَّرونَ
Because these are people, who want to be pure.
See how the good becomes bad and the bad becomes good, how the concepts are turned upside down.
The people of Lut(لوط) are saying; Kick Lut(لوط) out.
Why?
Because they want to be pure.
You're supposed to be impure.
If you want to stay here, you cannot be pure.
In other words, they're saying that our law does not protect the pure people.
If you want to be cleaned, then you're in the wrong place,
the same thing with Muslims, if now you're living in the West, if you are going to follow the rules of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى be pure
you are looked at as fundamentalist or extremist you have to go with this society in this impurities and dirt to get along.
This is the Tahara(طهارة) and they were upset because the people of Lut(لوط) have Tahara(طهارة) they wanted them to leave.
And then they said;
If you seize not O Lut(لوط), verily you will be one of those who are driven out.
Lut(لوط), even though he's alone, but he's telling them in public the truth.
قَالَ إِنِّي لِعَمَلِكُم مِّنَ الْقَالِينَ۝
Realize and know that I disapprove severely and strongly what you are doing.
I'm not going to get along with you, I do not approve what you're doing.
And then he made a Dua(دُعَا);
رَبِّ نَجِّني وَأَهلي مِمّا يَعمَلونَ۝
My Lord saved me and my family from what they do.
In another part of the world; Ibrahim عليه السّلام received three guests, three men.
They came in the house of Ibrahim عليه السّلام
Ibrahim عليه السّلام, the father of generosity.
He went out and got a calf and he slaughtered it.
They say that the two requirements of generosity are number one quality and quantity.
For you to be generous, you have to provide good quality and you have to provide the right quantity.
That's the two conditions of generosity, quality and quantity.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says about this calf that Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) presented to the people
in one Ayah(آية), it says, Ijl Sameen(عجل سمين), it was a fat calf.
And in the other Ayah(آية), it says Ijl Haniz(عجل حنيذ) it is a roasted calf.
So one Ayah(آية) is talking about the quality of that food, it was excellent quality, it was roasted.
So it was very well cooked.
And the other Ayah(آية) is telling us about the quantity of the food,
and that is Ijl Sameen(عجل سمين), it was fat, it was enough for them.
So Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) fulfilled the two requirements of generosity, the quality and the quantity.
So he presented them with this calf, he slaughtered it and he cooked it, it's a lot of effort.
And he presented it to these three guests.
But the amazing thing, or the shocking thing to Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) is that they didn't eat.
Travelers must be hungry, and they didn't eat.
Ibrahim عليه السّلام was afraid.
He started feeling mistrust towards them.
فَلَمَّا رَءَآ أَيْدِيَهُمْ لَا تَصِلُ إِلَيْهِ نَكِرَهُمْ وَأَوْجَسَ مِنْهُمْ خِيفَةً ۚ
But when he saw, their hands went not towards the meal, he felt some mistrust of them and conceived a fear of them.
They said;
قالوا لا تَخَف
Do not be afraid.
قالوا لا تَخَف إِنّا أُرسِلنا إِلىٰ قَومِ لوطٍ۝
We are messengers of Allah sent to the people of Lut(لوط).
These three men were angels, send by Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to the people of Lut(لوط).
Immediately when they said this statement, Sayeditna Sara(سيدتنا سارة) was in the background listening to them.
And when she heard that these three Messengers;
Messengers is angels,
when these three messengers are going to punish the people of Lut(لوط), She laughed;
فضحك
she laughed;
Why did she laughed?
We should have hatred in our hearts of evil.
And we should be happy and pleased when the punishment comes on evil.
So Sayeditna Sara(سيدتنا سارة) when she heard the news, that these evil people are going to be destroyed, she was happy.
Obviously, maybe many of us don't understand this concept.
What we understand is,
when my team wins in soccer, or when my team wins in basketball or football, that's when we're happy and that's when we're cheering.
But with the Saliheen(صالحين), the righteous; these are the games that they watch, and this is what they're happy for.
And it's not the game; it's the conflict between good and evil,
and they're happy when good wins and they're upset when evil wins.
So Sayeditna Sara(سيدتنا سارة) was happy when she heard the news that the people of Lut(لوط) are going to be destroyed.
When she laughed, what was the response of the angels, the three men,
these angels were in the form of men.
وَامرَأَتُهُ قائِمَةٌ فَضَحِكَت فَبَشَّرناها بِإِسحاقَ وَمِن وَراءِ إِسحاقَ يَعقوبَ۝
We gave her the glad tidings of Is'haq(إسحاق),
وَمِن وَراءِ إِسحاقَ يَعقوبَ۝
And after Is'haq(إسحاق) Yaqoob(يعقوب); Jacob.
So they gave her now glad tidings.
We also came to give you the glad tidings that you will have a son; his name will be his Is'haq(إسحاق)
and then your son Is'haq(إسحاق), will have a son and he is Yaqoob(يعقوب).
She slapped her face
فسكت وجه
she slapped her face and said I am an old woman and my husband is old.
How can we have a child ?
إِنَّ هٰذا لَشَيءٌ عَجيبٌ
She said: This is a strange thing.
She slapped her face, in amazement and she fround.
هذا امرٌ عجيب ، هٰذا لَشَيءٌ عَجيبٌ
This is a strange thing.
The angels told her;
أَتَعجَبينَ مِن أَمرِ اللَّهِ ۖ
Is the order and commandment of Allah; Strange.
This is there's nothing strange; Allah سبحانه وتعالى - Kunfa Yakoon(كن فيكون), he will tell anything to be, and it will become.
وَٱمْرَأَتُهُۥ قَآئِمَةٌ فَضَحِكَتْ فَبَشَّرْنَٰهَا بِإِسْحَٰقَ وَمِن وَرَآءِ إِسْحَٰقَ يَعْقُوبَ۝
They said: Do you wonder at the decree of Allah, the mercy of Allah and His Blessings to be on you - Oh family of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم).
Surely He; Allah is all praised in, and all glorious.
رحمة الله وبركاته عليكم اهل البيت
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is giving the blessings and the mercy on the household of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم), it's the blessed household.
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and Sara(سارة) received the glad tidings of a son.
They were given the glad tidings.
And this is after Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) already had his son; Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
They were very old in age maybe over 100 years old.
They're given the news that they would have a child and his name would be Is'haq(إسحاق).
And then after Is'haq(إسحاق); Yaqoob(يعقوب),
the Jews say that Is'haq(إسحاق) was the one, who was sacrificed and not Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
Now, how can Is'haq(إسحاق) to be sacrificed?
When Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and Sara(سارة) were told that Is'haq(إسحاق) would live and would have a son and his son would Yaqoob(يعقوب).
What's the point in telling Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) to sacrifice Is'haq(إسحاق)
if Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) already knows that Is'haq(إسحاق) would live and would have son and his son is Yaqoob(يعقوب).
This shows you that the Jews, because of their jealousy and hatred,
they tried to change everything, take everything from Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) and give it to Is'haq(إسحاق).
All of them are the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah and Allah gives honoring to whomever He wills.
Anyway, this is something on the side.
Now, in this meeting, the angels delivered this news that you would have a child and his name is Is'haq(إسحاق).
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) is thinking about something else.
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) is concerned;
we would expect that Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) would be concerned about the news that he would have a son;
No.
He was thinking about something else.
He's thanked Allahسُبحانه وتعالى that Allah will give him Is'haq(إسحاق)
but he is concerned, he's thinking about something else at that moment.
And he just waited and then the conversation about Is'haq(إسحاق) and Yaqoob(يعقوب) was over.
And then he said;
فَلَمّا ذَهَبَ عَن إِبراهيمَ الرَّوعُ وَجاءَتهُ البُشرىٰ يُجادِلُنا في قَومِ لوطٍ۝
إِنَّ إِبراهيمَ لَحَليمٌ أَوّاهٌ مُنيبٌ۝
Then when the fear had gone away from the mind of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم)
and the glad tidings has reached him, he began to plead with us for the people have Lut(لوط).
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) was concerned.
The angels said that they will destroy the people of Lut(لوط).
The Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) was concerned for two reasons.
First of all, Lut(لوط) was still there.
And in another Ayah(آية), Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) is telling the angels Lut(لوط) is there.
Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) is concerned because his nephew, the righteous Nabi(نَبِي) of Allah; Lut(لوط) is still in the village.
And Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) thought that maybe the punishment will come and destroy everyone in the village.
And Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) also because of his gentleness, and His mercy; he was pleading for the people of Lut(لوط).
He wanted to give them another chance maybe they would repent to Allah and believe;
so he's pleading for them, give them another chance, but the angels told him;
يا إِبراهيمُ أَعرِض عَن هٰذا ۖ إِنَّهُ قَد جاءَ أَمرُ رَبِّكَ ۖ وَإِنَّهُم آتيهِم عَذابٌ غَيرُ مَردودٍ۝
O Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) leave this issue alone; Leave this matter alone.
إِنَّهُ قَد جاءَ أَمرُ رَبِّكَ ۖ
The order of Allah has already been revealed.
There's no change in it;
you cannot plead for this;
you cannot make any Shafa'a(شفاعة) in this.
The order of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى the commandment of Allah has already descended.
And they said;
وَإِنَّهُم آتيهِم عَذابٌ غَيرُ مَردودٍ۝
And verily there will come a tournament for them that cannot be turned back.
The punishment there is no way it can be turned back; that's it.
The angels left,
they came to Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) to deliver to him news and that is Is'haq(إسحاق) and Yaqoob(يعقوب)
and they left on their way to fulfill their mission.
They're heading to Sadoom(سدوم).
When they reach to the outskirts of the town.
It is said that the first one, who saw them was the daughter of Lut(لوط).
She saw these three handsome young men she immediately rushed towards her father
and told him: My father, there are three young handsome men coming in town.
The father immediately rushed outside, to meet them,
and to tell them; Be my guests.
Because Lut(لوط) knows if they are not his guests,
they're going to be guests with somebody else in the people of Sadoom(سدوم).
If he does not take care of them, they would be in trouble.
And these are three young handsome men.
Lut(لوط) was walking into the town, he was walking in front of them to make sure that nobody will see them.
If they're seen they would be in trouble.
So he's leading them in the streets of the town and then Lut(لوط), looked back at them and said;
ولله ما أعلم على وجه الأرض أحد أفسد نهاية من هذه القرية
He said: In the name of Allah, I don't know of anyone on the face of the earth who is more evil than these people.
They didn't respond.
He turned again to them and said;
In the name of Allah, I don't know that there's anyone on the face of the earth more evil than these people.
What is Lut(لوط) trying to do?
Lut(لوط) does not want to tell them; leave.
He doesn't want to say explicitly leave.
Because they might interpret it as he doesn't want to host us.
So let's leave him alone and go and find somebody else.
He doesn't want to do that.
Because he knows if they go and find another host, they would be in trouble.
But he wants to give them a correct assessment of the situation.
He thinks that these are foreigners, they don't know what's going on.
So he wants to tell them; Do you know where you're going?
Do you know what town is this?
Do you know the evil that is happening here?
So that they would take the initiative and leave on their own.
And he kept on doing that again and again, three or four or five times?
Every now and then he would turn back and say these are the most evil people; these people are corrupt.
Lut(لوط) doesn't know what's happening.
Lut(لوط) is speaking to these three men and he does not know what's happening.
Because Ibn Kathir(اِبْنِ كَثِيْر) says
that these three angels in the form of men, were given instructions by Allahسُبحانه وتعالى,
that you do not destroy the people of Lut(لوط); until you hear the witness of their Nabi(نَبِي) against them.
So the angels were recording everything Lut(لوط) was saying, because here's their Nabi(نَبِي),
they have to hear what he says about them.
He is the one, who will be asked about them on the Day of Judgment.
So before these people are punished, they need to get the most important witness, and that is the witness of their own Nabi(نَبِي).
So the angel was silent, and they were recording everything; Lut(لوط) was saying.
These people are most evil people on the face of the earth, and they just are writing that down.
They got the witness of Lut(لوط), and now they can go ahead with the punishment.
Lut(لوط) is see that these three men are not getting the point
and they're following him and things are getting more difficult on him.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is describing to us the situation of Lut(لوط);
وَلَمَّا جَآءَتْ رُسُلُنَا لُوطًا سِىٓءَ بِهِمْ وَضَاقَ بِهِمْ ذَرْعًا وَقَالَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَصِيبٌ۝
And when our messengers came to Lut(لوط), he was grieved on their account.
And he was feeling pressure, he was feeling uncomfortable.
Imagine the situation of Lut(لوط) very difficult situation he needs to protect these three men.
And then he took them into his house and he closed the doors; nobody saw them.
So who leaked the news?
The wife of Lut(لوط).
The wife of Lut(لوط) left and she went to the people of Lut(لوط)
and she told them that there are three handsome men in our house.
She was collaborating with them;
ضَرَبَ اللَّهُ مَثَلًا لِلَّذينَ كَفَرُوا امرَأَتَ نوحٍ وَامرَأَتَ لوطٍ ۖ
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
The example of the non believing woman is the wife of Noh(نوح) and the wife of Lut(لوط).
She was collaborating with the people of Lut(لوط)
and she is the one who leaked out the information that these three men are in town.
She went and told them this.
The news was spreading and the crowds were gathering in the streets.
They were coming out of their clubs, rushing in the streets, crowds are rushing in the streets.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَجَآءَ أَهْلُ ٱلْمَدِينَةِ يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ۝
And the inhabitants of the city, came rejoicing, happy, celebrating,
and writing and demonstrations were outside of the house of Lut(لوط).
And there was a crowd; imagine huge crowd of men celebrating and dancing and singing;
يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ
they're happy.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى describes this evil scene.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
لَعمرك
in your life, Muhammadﷺ is the only person, whom Allahسُبحانه وتعالى makes an oath; in his life.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى makes an oath in anything of His creation; we can only make an oath in Allah.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has made an oath and no other human being in Qur'an except Muhammadﷺ
لَعمرك
in your life.
Allah is making an oath in the life of Muhammadﷺ.
What does the Allah say?
لَعَمرُكَ إِنَّهُم لَفي سَكرَتِهِم يَعمَهونَ۝
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says verily by your life, they are in their wild intoxication, wondering blindly.
Sakra(سكرة), they were drunk, but they were not drunk because of alcohol.
They were not intoxicated because of alcohol; they were intoxicated by their lust, desires and especially sexual desires.
They can blind the person, they can literally blind the heart.
It can make a person drunk, obsessed, blind,
أعمل بصيرة
and that was the situation of the people of Lut(لوط).
Lut(لوط) came out to his people.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَجاءَهُ قَومُهُ يُهرَعونَ إِلَيهِ وَمِن قَبلُ كانوا يَعمَلونَ السَّيِّئَاتِ ۚ
And his people came rushing towards him.
Lut(لوط) told these people.
قال إن هؤلاء ضيفي فلا تفضحون ۝
واتقوا الله ولا تخزون ۝
Verily, these are my guests do not shame me.
فَاتَّقُوا اللَّهَ وَلا تُخزونِ۝
And fear Allah and do not disgrace me.
What is this disgrace you're going to cause on me.
These are my guests.
They told him Lut(لوط).
قَالُوٓاْ أَوَلَمْ نَنْهَكَ عَنِ ٱلْعَٰلَمِينَ۝
Didn't we prohibit you from hosting any guests?
By their corrupt law, by their law.
They have already placed some restrictions on Lut(لوط).
They told them: You are not allowed to host any guests.
And then Lut(لوط) told them.
قالَ هٰؤُلاءِ بَناتي إِن كُنتُم فاعِلينَ۝
Here are my daughter's marry them.
He's not talking about his own daughters.
He's talking about the daughters of the Ummah(امة) because he's like their father.
He said, Here are the daughters.
They said;
ما لنا
we don't have any need in your daughter's; You know what we want?
إنك لا تعلم ما نريد
You know what we want; We want your guests.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى describes this difficult critical situation;
crowds celebrating outside and writing outside the house of Lut(لوط), pushing the door to come in.
Lut(لوط) said;
هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَصِيبٌ
This is a distressful difficult day.
What a difficult day.
The pressure was building on Lut(لوط) building and building and building he is carrying all of this pressure on his shoulders.
He then said;
هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَصِيبٌ
This is a distressful day.
He's trying his best, but he's losing grounds.
And when he felt that this is a hopeless case, and that he's losing this battle, he wanted help.
But Lut(لوط) did not belong to that town, so he didn't have any family to help him.
He didn't have a tribal support; to support him.
And Lut(لوط) didn't have any sons, he had daughters.
He didn't have any men to fight with him; he was alone.
In that moment of difficulty in that critical moment and extreme moments of distress on Sayedina Lut(سيدنالوط).
He said the following statement;
قَالَ لَوْ أَنَّ لِى بِكُمْ قُوَّةً أَوْ ءَاوِىٓ إِلَىٰ رُكْنٍۢ شَدِيدٍۢ۝
If only I had a source of power to lean on.
I wish that I have a source of power to lean on; So, that I can fight you.
family or tribe or men or sons.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says;
يرحم الله لوط
May Allah have mercy on Lut(لوط), he had the strongest source of power with him; Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
In that particular moment when Lut(لوط) said that statement;
I wish that I can kneel on some source of power.
In that moment, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says that the angel said;
قالوا يا لوطُ إِنّا رُسُلُ رَبِّكَ لَن يَصِلوا إِلَيكَ ۖ
Oh Lut(لوط), we are the messengers of Allah, they will not reach you and harm you.
These three men finally spoke out in that moment, just one second before the defeat of Lut(لوط)
because that's what these men were crowding and were breaking in.
And in that moment in which Lut(لوط) said: I wish that I have a source of power to lean on.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: He had the strongest power with him.
He had Allahسُبحانه وتعالى on his side.
The angel then spoke up and said;
Oh, Lut(لوط), we are the messengers of Allah; Do not fear and they will not reach you.
And then they said;
فَأَسرِ بِأَهلِكَ بِقِطعٍ مِنَ اللَّيلِ وَلا يَلتَفِت مِنكُم أَحَدٌ إِلَّا امرَأَتَكَ ۖ
إِلَّا امرَأَتَكَ ۖ إِنَّهُ مُصيبُها ما أَصابَهُم ۚ إِنَّ مَوعِدَهُمُ الصُّبحُ ۚ أَلَيسَ الصُّبحُ بِقَريبٍ۝
Leave with your family in the darkness of the night.
وَلا يَلتَفِت مِنكُم أَحَدٌ
And nobody of you look back; when you leave do not look back.
إِلَّا امرَأَتَكَ ۖ
Except your wife.
There are two interpretations on this.
One interpretation is that do not take your wife with you, leave her in town.
The other interpretation is that she would leave with you but then she would look back and she would be killed.
إِنَّهُ مُصيبُها ما أَصابَهُم ۚ
She would be punished with the same punishment they are punished.
And then they said;
إِنَّ مَوعِدَهُمُ الصُّبحُ ۚ أَلَيسَ الصُّبحُ بِقَريبٍ
Their appointed time is morning; Isn't morning soon.?
Lut(لوط) left, under darkness of night with his daughters and his family.
Early in the morning with sunrise when Lut(لوط) is already away from Sedoon(سدون); he walked away.
Suddenly; أصيحة ; the awful cry attacked the people of Lut(لوط)
and then the angel Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) transformed out of this human form into his original angelic form.
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل), which was in the form of a man came out in his angelic form to fill the horizon with 700 wings.
And then Jibreel عليه السّلام with the tip of his wing,
with the tip of his wings; not with all wing; with the tip of his wing;
scraped up, the whole town of the people of Lut(لوط)
and raised them up in the sky,
and then flip them upside down and smash them back to Earth.
And then Allahسُبحانه وتعالى sent on them stones, everyone received the stone with his name.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has never ever combined such a punishment on any people in history.
They were afflicted with the awful cry
and then they were raised up and turned upside down.
And then they received missiles from the sky to destroy them all and to exterminate them from the face of the earth.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
فَأَخَذَتهُمُ الصَّيحَةُ مُشرِقينَ۝
فَجَعَلنا عالِيَها سافِلَها وَأَمطَرنا عَلَيهِم حِجارَةً مِن سِجّيلٍ۝
إِنَّ في ذٰلِكَ لَآياتٍ لِلمُتَوَسِّمينَ۝
The awful cry overtook them at the time of sunrise,
and we turn them upside down and rain down on them stones of baked clay.
Surely, in this our science for those who see.
I want to close with this verse.
But before that, let's look at the conditions we're living in.
We're living now in a society that is starting to recognize homosexuals as a minority group that deserves special status
and deserves special rights.
We are living in a society that now is publicly promoting this in media, TV movies.
We're living in a society that is now officially in some places marrying them.
We are living in a society that regards them as a group that needs to be defended.
These things that exist in America and the West today,
we need to understand and realize according to my information, according to my knowledge,
never ever in the history of mankind, since Lut(لوط) until now,
whether we're talking about pagans, or Muslims, or Christians, or Jews or any other religion,
never has this sin, been promoted publicly as it is being promoted today in the West.
And look at all of the societies of the world; I'm not talking about Muslims only.
This is something that is not viewed with any respect in any religion.
In every culture and society, whether we're talking about Asia, India or China, Japan, Africa, Europe up to this time,
nobody in the world since the time of Lut(لوط), until now;
allowed such a sin to be promoted publicly, and to be sanctified by the law,
except the societies of the West that we are living in today.
And we need to realize that if this sin is promoted and becomes public, and is protected by law,
then Allahسُبحانه وتعالى will bring down his punishment
because Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَما هِيَ مِنَ الظّالِمينَ بِبَعيدٍ۝
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى after this Ayaat(آيات) of Lut(لوط), says;
And this punishment is not far away from the evildoers,
this punishment will come down on any society that promotes such a sin.
This sin does exist in every society of the world, but it's underground,
and that people despise it, and that people dislike it,
and they make fun of anybody who commits it and they are outcasts of this society.
In any place in the world, Muslim or non Muslim, except in the West today, it is looked upon right now,
and we could get to that stage in the future, where for some people, they view it as an honor.
That is how evil things became.
This is the perception we need to have about this sin, that this is something that Allahسُبحانه وتعالى will not allow to happen.
And this is something that will draw the punishment of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى
and we make our voice clear, and we say;
We disapprove the sin, we disapprove it severely.
We view that this is Haram(حرام) and then it should be punished.
And we do not approve of any public promotion of such a sin.
And we'll make it a statement that we say aloud and clearly to everyone and we're not afraid
and we say, even if they accuse us of discrimination, or accuse us of extremism or fundamentalism, this is our religion.
This is the religion of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
قالَ إِنّي لِعَمَلِكُم مِنَ القالينَ۝
We severely disapproved this.
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّم